# Aimee, Xuan QI

Mobile phone: 65- 8556 0169 E-mail: aimeechiqi@gmail.com

## Summary

Place of Birth Beijing

Nationality Hong Kong Permanent Resident

Residence Singapore

Language(s) English and Mandarin

Successful sales professional with extensive experience in Greater China and South East Asia and wide connection with financial institutions and high net worth individuals. Strong financial product knowledge in financial products across different asset classes. A committed and self-motivated team player with excellent communication and interpersonal skills. Fluent in English and Mandarin.

## **Professional Experience**

## Bloomberg L.P. Singapore

## Aug 2014 to Jun 2017

## Fixed Income and Derivatives Valuation - South East Asia Specialist

Responsible for developing Fixed Income and cross-assets derivatives valuation business in SEA Regions including Singapore, Malaysia,Brunei, Philippines, Indonesia and India etc.

Major clients include Regional Banks, PBs, Asset Managers and Sovereign Wealth Funds in the region.

Note: From Mar 2013 to July 2014, taking time off to take care of my child.

## **Barclays Capital Asia Limited**

May 2010 - Feb 2013

## Director, Multi Assets Sales, Hong Kong

Responsible for developing China Institutional business and providing cross assets investment products and asset allocation solutions to leading onshore and offshore Chinese financial institutions.

Successfully developed Barclays Fixed Income and Cash Equity business in China.

Major clients include sovereign wealth funds, top tier and second tier banks, private banks, asset managers and HNW clients in China and HK.

## **China Investment Corporation (CIC)**

May 2010 - Nov 2010

### Secondee, Relative Value Investment Department, Beijing

Worked in CIC under a 6 months secondment arrangement between Barclays and CIC to facilitate the fixed income tactical asset allocation and relative value investment.

Built up good relationship with Fixed Income, Equity, Alternative Investment Department of CIC

## Man Investments (Hong Kong) Limited

Apr 2009 - May 2010

#### Director, Sales-China Market, Hong Kong

Responsible for developing the hedge funds business in the asset management, retail banking and private banking areas in China, HK.

Worked closely with China Merchant Bank PB to provide hedge fund linked products to its high net worth clients in China, HK and Taiwan.

## **BNP Paribas Hong Kong Branch**

Aug 2005 - Jan 2009

## Director, Equity & Derivatives Sales, Hong Kong

Responsible for developing equity-derivatives business in China.

Successfully introduced equity- and fund-linked structured products to institutional and HNW clients in China. Major clients include onshore and offshore entities in China and HK..

## ING Bank N.V. Hong Kong

May 2004 - Jun 2005

## Vice President, Cross Products Sales, Financial Market, Hong Kong

Responsible for providing fixed income and FX linked solutions to major Chinese banks including ICBC, BOC, ABC, CCB and second tier banks. Major products included snowball, target redemption, CMS DRA etc.

Deals volume ranked No. 1 in ICBC's wealth management business

#### COFCO, Head Office

Apr 1998 - Apr 2004

## Senior Manager, Treasury Division, Beijing

Responsible for coordinating projects in restructuring, M&A, listed company asset injection projects and overseas short-term and long-term financing programs.

Responsible for investing into yield enhance products including CLN, Dual currency deposits etc to improve the return of the group's foreign currency assets as well as hedging solutions..

#### Education

#### Central University of Finance and Economics, Beijing

Sep 1995 - Jan 1998

Master of Economics in Accounting with Honors

### Central University of Finance and Economics, Beijing

Sep 1991 – Jul 1995

Bachelor of Economics in Accounting with Honors

#### **Professional Qualifications**

Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA), since Aug 2006

Non-practical Certified Public Accountant (CPA), since Sept 1996

Chinese Institution of Certified Public Accountant (CICPA), since Sept 1996

#### References

Available upon request